Contact

rushilsingh@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/rushilsingh (LinkedIn) rushilsingh.dev (Personal)

Top Skills

docker

DevOps

Kubernetes

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
Hindi (Native or Bilingual)
Punjabi (Native or Bilingual)

Honors-Awards

President's Entrance Scholarship

Publications

Dating Profile Age Analysis – a Supervised Learning Application

Rushil Singh

Full-Stack Software Engineer | Cloud & Data Specialist India

Summary

With over six years of experience, I am a proficient software engineer specializing in Python-driven AWS data engineering pipelines, full-stack application development utilizing JavaScript frameworks, and cross-platform app creation with Flutter. My expertise in serverless architectures, adherence to clean coding principles, and commitment to lifelong learning have consistently resulted in the successful delivery of top-notch projects.

Experience

Synamedia Software Engineer February 2020 - Present (3 years 3 months) Bengaluru Area, India

- As a Software Engineer at Synamedia, I have been instrumental in the development of anti-piracy and addressable advertising solutions.
- An area of focus has been data engineering pipelines in AWS, most often driven by Python code.
- I have built full-stack applications, chiefly using a MEAN stack.
- Recently, I have also been developing cross-platform solutions using Flutter.

Volen Software Services Pvt. Ltd., Software Engineer September 2019 - February 2020 (6 months) Bengaluru Area, India

- Played a pivotal role in developing an anti-piracy solution for Synamedia, a leading provider of video infrastructure solutions, while working as a Software Engineer at Volen Software Services
- Focused on Python-based frameworks to develop high-quality, client-oriented software solutions
- Offered a full-time role at Synamedia due to outstanding performance and ability to deliver top-tier solutions, further advancing career in the software engineering field

ACL Digital Software Engineer May 2017 - June 2019 (2 years 2 months) Bengaluru Area, India

- Managed orchestration of network devices, appliances, and virtual appliances in the SDN and NFV space
- Developed Resource Adapters to communicate with devices on the southbound interface using device-specific protocols and converted retrieved data to JSON for use by other north-bound REST applications

The University of British Columbia Teaching Assistant January 2013 - April 2013 (4 months) Vancouver, Canada Area

- Acquired experience in course administration, curriculum development, and student mentorship as a Teaching Assistant for the Cognitive Systems course (COGS 300) at The University of British Columbia
- Acted as a bridge between students and the professor, facilitating feedback, problem-solving, and efficient course management
- Crafted laboratory tasks, supervised lab sessions, maintained and moderated the course website, and assessed lab reports and exams

Education

The University of British Columbia
Bachelor of Science (BSc), Cognitive Systems · (2016)

The Doon School

Indian School Certificate (ISC), Physics, Chemistry, Mathematics, Computer Science, English